<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Industrial on Amrit Singhal</title>
    <link>https://amr4i.github.io/tags/industrial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Industrial on Amrit Singhal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Amrit Singhal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amr4i.github.io/tags/industrial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Reality Authoring</title>
      <link>https://amr4i.github.io/project/augmented-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amr4i.github.io/project/augmented-reality/</guid>
      <description>Location This project was done as a research internship at Big Data Experience Lab, Adobe Systems, Bangalore during May &amp;lsquo;18 - Jul &amp;lsquo;18, the summer of my third year.
Details During the internship, I worked as a Research Intern, among a team of 3 members and in close coordination with multiple research members of technical staff at the company, to accomplish the above-mentioned project. A general area of interest was assigned, and a specific problem statement was chosen in that area after an extensive period of brainstorming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Independent Text-to-Emotion Classification</title>
      <link>https://amr4i.github.io/project/language-independent-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amr4i.github.io/project/language-independent-emotion/</guid>
      <description>Location This project was done as a industrial software internship at Hike Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, during May &amp;lsquo;17 - Jul &amp;lsquo;17, the summer of my second year.
Details The project aimed at developing a machine learning model to assign an emotion to any chat message provided as input. This would allow quick sticker recommendations to be based not only the textual reference, but also take into account the emotional state of the user for that message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for large scale logistics platform</title>
      <link>https://amr4i.github.io/project/nyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amr4i.github.io/project/nyo/</guid>
      <description>Location This project was done as a remote software development internship at New York Office, IIT Kanpur during May &amp;lsquo;18 - Jul &amp;lsquo;18, the summer of my second year.
Details The project comprised of completing multiple tasks within the assigned duration of the internship. The first task was to implement the Document Distance problem, to remove the semantically same articles from large collection of articles. This was accomplished by using word vectors and document vectors and implementing the Word Mover’s Distance algorithm to successfully eliminate all similar entries within acceptable error values.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>