<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Amrit Singhal</title>
    <link>amr4i.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Amrit Singhal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Amrit Singhal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="amr4i.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Reality Authoring</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/augmented-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/augmented-reality/</guid>
      <description>Location This project was done as a research internship at Big Data Experience Lab, Adobe Systems, Bangalore during May &amp;lsquo;18 - Jul &amp;lsquo;18, the summer of my third year.
Details During the internship, I worked as a Research Intern, among a team of 3 members and in close coordination with multiple research members of technical staff at the company, to accomplish the above-mentioned project. A general area of interest was assigned, and a specific problem statement was chosen in that area after an extensive period of brainstorming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross Modal Media Retrieval</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/cross-modal-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/cross-modal-media/</guid>
      <description>Details This project was done as my first undergraduate research project under Prof. Medha Atre, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur.
Abstract This project aims to utilize the the emotional information present in any media to perform cross-modal media retrieval efficiently. We present an implementation to extract this emotion from images as 2-dimensional vectors, and propose two methods to bring this emotion vectors from different medias in the same space, one being a statistical approach, and the other being a learning based approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Independent Text-to-Emotion Classification</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/language-independent-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/language-independent-emotion/</guid>
      <description>Location This project was done as a industrial software internship at Hike Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, during May &amp;lsquo;17 - Jul &amp;lsquo;17, the summer of my second year.
Details The project aimed at developing a machine learning model to assign an emotion to any chat message provided as input. This would allow quick sticker recommendations to be based not only the textual reference, but also take into account the emotional state of the user for that message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for large scale logistics platform</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/nyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/nyo/</guid>
      <description>Location This project was done as a remote software development internship at New York Office, IIT Kanpur during May &amp;lsquo;18 - Jul &amp;lsquo;18, the summer of my second year.
Details The project comprised of completing multiple tasks within the assigned duration of the internship. The first task was to implement the Document Distance problem, to remove the semantically same articles from large collection of articles. This was accomplished by using word vectors and document vectors and implementing the Word Mover’s Distance algorithm to successfully eliminate all similar entries within acceptable error values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Machine Translation for Low Resource Languages</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/neural-machine-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/neural-machine-translation/</guid>
      <description>Details This project was done as part of the course CS671: Introduction to Natural Language Processing, in the Spring &amp;lsquo;18 term at IIT Kanpur under Prof. Harish Karnick, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur.
Abstract Much work has been done on Neural Machine Translation, but most of it requires the availability of a large parallel corpora to train on, which is not always readily available. Unsupervised methods also exist that work by encoding both the languages in consideration to a common latent space, and then decoding them to the target language as required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Machine Learning</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/quantum-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/quantum-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Details This project was done as research project in the course CS682: Quantum Computing, in the Fall &amp;lsquo;17 term at IIT Kanpur under Prof. Rajat Mittal, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur.
Abstract The aim of the project is to study two of the most widely used machine learning strategies, namely KNearest Neighbours algorithm and Perceptron Learning algorithm, in a quantum setting, and study the speedups that the quantum modules allow over the classical counterparts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Biased Multi-Dcoument Abstractive Summarisation</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/query-abs-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/query-abs-summary/</guid>
      <description>Details This project was started as part of the course CS657: Information Retrieval, in the Spring &amp;lsquo;18 term at IIT Kanpur under Prof. Arnab Bhattacharya, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur. It has been continued beyond the course into my second undergraduate research project, and is still in progress.
Abstract In this project, we introduced a novel pipeline to implement a query-biased multi-document abstractive summarisation. Traditional information retrieval systems return a ranked list of whole documents as the answer to a query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewer Recommendation for Conference Paper Submissions</title>
      <link>amr4i.github.io/project/reviewer-recommendation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>amr4i.github.io/project/reviewer-recommendation/</guid>
      <description>Details This project was done as part of the course CS771: Machine Learning Techniques, in the Fall &amp;lsquo;17 term at IIT Kanpur under Prof. Purushottam Kar, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur.
Abstract The process of reviewer assignment to the papers of a conference is a very challenging and sensitive task. The choice of reviewers for a particular paper plays a crucial role in determining whether the paper is accepted into the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>