<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>information-retrieval | Amrit Singhal</title>
    <link>https://amr4i.github.io/tags/information-retrieval/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://amr4i.github.io/tags/information-retrieval/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>information-retrieval</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Amrit Singhal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://amr4i.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>information-retrieval</title>
      <link>https://amr4i.github.io/tags/information-retrieval/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Biased Multi-Document Abstractive Summarisation</title>
      <link>https://amr4i.github.io/project/query-abs-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amr4i.github.io/project/query-abs-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was started as part of the course &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cse.iitk.ac.in/pages/CS657.html&#34;&gt;CS657: Information Retrieval&lt;/a&gt;, in the Spring &amp;lsquo;18 term at IIT Kanpur under &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cse.iitk.ac.in/users/arnabb/&#34;&gt;Prof. Arnab Bhattacharya&lt;/a&gt;, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur. It was later continued beyond the course into my second undergraduate research project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we introduced a novel pipeline to implement a query-biased multi-document
abstractive summarisation. Traditional information retrieval systems return a ranked
list of whole documents as the answer to a query. However, in many cases, not every part
of an entire document is relevant to the query. Thus, it is desirable to retrieve from
the set of retrieved documents, in a succinct manner, a summary of only the required
information extracted from across all the relevant documents. The approach proposed
involves retrieving relevant documents for each query, followed by extracting relevant
passages from each document. This is followed by collating all such relevant passages
and performing redundancy removal to keep the length of such a collated document sane.
Finally, an abstractive summarisation approach is used to generate abstractive single-line
summaries for our information need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross Modal Media Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://amr4i.github.io/project/cross-modal-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amr4i.github.io/project/cross-modal-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was done as my first undergraduate research project under &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.ox.ac.uk/people/medha.atre/&#34;&gt;Prof. Medha Atre&lt;/a&gt;, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to utilize the the emotional information present in any media to perform cross-modal media
retrieval efficiently. We present an implementation to extract this emotion from images as 2-dimensional
vectors, and propose two methods to bring this emotion vectors from different medias in the same space, one
being a statistical approach, and the other being a learning based approach. We also present a hypothesis,
which allows us to establish a ground truth for the cross modal mapping. We perform extensive analysis of
one of our proposals, and report the results obtained. We have also proposed and implemented a heuristic
to retrieve cross-modal results efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
